Guide to the Targ Editions Archive, 1953-1994 (Bulk 1979-1985) MSS.149
Fales Library and Special Collections
Targ Editions Archive
1953-1994
1979-1985
Fales Library and Special Collections
Targ Editions
MSS.149
3.75 Linear Feet in 10 boxes
In 1979 book editor William Targ founded Targ Editions, a one-man operation that published books by contemporary authors, poets, and playwrights. There are twenty-five Targ Editions volumes, each a limited edition produced by letter press. Targ Editions includes work by Henry Roth, Saul Bellow, John Updike, Tennessee Williams, and Ray Bradbury. The Targ Editions Archive documents the publication of the Targ Editions books, through correspondence with authors, agents, printers, records of financial transactions, order requests from book sellers and collectors, press clippings and book reviews, and production materials such as manuscripts, paper samples, unbound signatures, and author photographs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated by Roslyn Targ in 2003 and 2018.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Biographical Note
William Targ (1907-1999) was a successful book editor and well respected in the field of commercial publishing. He is perhaps best known for publishing Mario Puzo's novel The Godfather while editor in chief of G. P. Putnam's Sons.
Targ was born in Chicago to Russian immigrants. His name was originally William Torgownik. A high-school dropout with a passion for books and letterpress printing, Targ took a job as an office boy at Macmillan when he was 18. He opened his own bookshop at 22. From 1942 to 1964 Targ worked as an editor for the World Publishing Company, eventually becoming editor in chief. He then moved to G.P. Putnam's Sons where, in 1968, he bought Puzo's novel for a $5000 advance. According to the New York Times, "'The Godfather' turned out to be the most profitable single novel ever published by Putnam's and the paperback rights were sold for more than $400,000."
Outside of the commercial realm, Targ was committed to the art of bookmanship and the ideals of the Private Press. After retiring from Putnam in 1978, he founded Targ Editions, a one-man operation he ran from his home in Greenwich Village. Targ sought to publish works by contemporary writers that had not been previously produced in book form. The twenty-five Targ Editions include works by Henry Roth, John Updike, Saul Bellow, Tennessee Williams, Isaac Asimov, Ray Bradbury, and Norman Mailer--each book a unique volume. As Targ wrote for his Targ Editions checklist: "Each of these books is individually designed (no two formats are alike) and they are produced by letter press and are hand-bound. The various printing papers are of high quality, and enduring—mainly of rag, and deckle-edged. The bindings are of pictorial or decorated boards, and or cloth over boards. Each book is signed by its author. The editions are limited to between 150 and 350 copies each." Copies of most of the Targ Editions volumes are housed in the Fales Library.
In his own Targ Editions volume, Abacus Now, William Targ wrote: "Print can be as beautiful as music; it has the power to move, it is as volatile as stage magic. As a typophile and bookman, now on my own, I look more closely into the genius and works of the men and women who enriched our lives with beautiful books. I observe closely the contemporary typographic scene, the people engaged with the magical 26 letters by which we live... I don't think the private press printer will save the world; but I think that if we are seeking the pure of heart and a wholesome commitment, such a person may be found more readily beside a hand press than, say, in an advertising agency or in the House of Representatives--or in City Hall." William Targ died on July 22, 1999, at the age of 92, in his Manhattan home.
References:
Targ, William. Abacus Now: Footnotes to Indecent Pleasures and Observations on Fine Book Printing, Book-Collecting and Matters Personal including How to Survive in the Computer Age. New York: Targ Editions, 1984.
"William Targ, 'Godfather' Editor, Dies at 92.",New York Times. 25 July, 1999.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of production materials for all the Targ Editions volumes. Materials include correspondence with authors, financial records, production and printing materials, financial documents including purchase orders and press and publicity materials.
Arrangement
The Targ Editions Archive is divided into 26 series: 1-24 each correspond to a different Targ Editions volume, and Series 25 consists of various oversize material. The series are arranged chronologically, beginning with Targ Editions No. 2, John Updike's Three Illuminations In the Life of an American Author, and ending with an unpublished piece by Gabriel Garcia Márquez, what would have been Targ Editions No. 26.
Series I: John Updike, Three Illuminations in the Life of an American Author, Targ Editions No. 2
Series II: Ray Bradbury, Beyond 1984: Remembrance of Things Little, Targ Editions No. 3
Series III: Saul Bellow, The Nobel Lecture, Targ Editions No. 4
Series IV: Kate Millett, Elegy for Sita, Targ Editions No. 5
Series V: Richard Brautigan. The Tokyo-Montana Express, Targ Editions No. 6
Series VI: Chester Himes, A Case of Rape, Targ Editions No. 7
Series VII: Laura Riding, Descriptions of Life, Targ Editions No. 8
Series VIII: Tennessee Williams, Steps Must Be Gentle, Targ Editions No. 9
Series IX: John Updike, Ego and Art in Walt Whitman, Targ Editions No. 10
Series X: Issac Asimov, Three By Asimov, Targ Editions No. 11
Series XI: John Updike, Hawthorne's Creed, Targ Editions No. 12
Series XII: Diane Wakoski, Saturn's Rings, Targ Editions No. 14
Series XIII: D.R. Benson, Irene, Good Night, Embellished by Edward Gorey, Targ Editions No. 15
Series XIV: Marguerite Yourcenar, The Alms of Alcippe, Targ Editions No. 16
Series XV: Theodore Low De Vinne, The First Editor: Aldus Pius Manutius, Woodcuts by Antonio Frasconi, Targ Editions No. 17
Series XVI: Jorge Amado, The Miracle of the Birds, Targ Editions No. 18
Series XVII: James A. Michener, Collectors, Forgers--And A Writer: A Memoir, Forward by John F. Fleming, Targ Editions No. 19
Series XVIII: W. D. Snodgrass, Vivaldi's Four Seasons, Targ Editions No. 20
Series XIX: Wallace Shawn, Our Late Night, Targ Editions No. 21
Series XX: Norman Mailer, The Last Night, Targ Editions No. 22
Series XXI: Eleanor Sullivan, Whodunit: A Biblio-Bio-Anecdotal Memoir of Frederic Dannay, Targ Editions No. 23
Series XXII: William Targ, Abacus Now: Footnotes to Indecent Pleasures and Observations on Fine Book Printing, Book-Collecting and Matters Personal including How to Survive in the Computer Age, Targ Editions No. 24
Series XXIII: M. F. K. Fisher, Spirits of the Valley, Targ Editions No. 25
Series XXIV: Gabriel Garcia Márquez, The Solitude of Latin America, unpublished
Series XXV: Oversize - Series I-XXIV
Series XXVI: William Targ, Secret Lives Manuscript
Related Material at Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Manuscript Collection (MSS.001)
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
American literature -- 20th century.; Authors, American -- 20th century.; Page proofs.; Financial records; Commercial correspondence; Legal correspondence.; Personal correspondence.; Scripts (documents); Publishers and publishing -- United States.; Private presses |z United States.; Reviews (document genre); Signatures (binders' notations).; Purchase orders.; Photographs.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; Manuscripts for publication.; Gorey, Edward, 1925-2000; Frasconi, Antonio; Mailer, Norman; Himes, Chester B., 1909-1984; Millett, Kate; Michener, James A. (James Albert), 1907-1997; Riding, Laura, 1901-1991; García Márquez, Gabriel, 1928-; Snodgrass, W. D. (William De Witt), 1926-2009; Shawn, Wallace; Sullivan, Eleanor; Updike, John; Targ, William, 1907-; Yourcenar, Marguerite; Wakoski, Diane; Amado, Jorge, 1912-2001; Asimov, Isaac, 1920-1992; Bellow, Saul; Bensen, D. R. (Donald R.), 1927-1997; Bradbury, Ray, 1920-; Brautigan, Richard; Fisher, M. F. K. (Mary Frances Kennedy), 1908-1992
- Series I: John Updike, Three Illuminations In the Life of an American Author, Targ Editions No. 2
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, production materials, and press related to the publication of John Updike's Three Illuminations by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Updike, Three Illuminations, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records, Updike, Three Illuminations, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Orders, Updike, Three Illuminations, March 9, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Original copy, Updike, Three Illuminations, August 21, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Original copy with author notes, Updike, Three Illuminations, August 21, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Unbound signatures, Updike, Three Illuminations, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Colophon page with signature, paper samples, Updike, Three Illuminations, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, Updike, Three Illuminations, July 13, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II: Ray Bradbury, Beyond 1984: Remembrance of Things Future, Targ Editions No. 3
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of Ray Bradbury's Beyond 1984 by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Bradbury, Beyond 1984, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Financial Records, Bradbury, Beyond 1984, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Orders, Bradbury, Beyond 1984, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript, Bradbury, Beyond 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript fragments with editorial revisions and layout notes, Bradbury, Beyond 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Unbound signatures, Bradbury, Beyond 1984, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sample title pages and text block, Bradbury, Beyond 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Half-tone screen prints, Ray Bradbury photograph, Bradbury, Beyond 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series III: Saul Bellow, The Nobel Lecture, Targ Editions No. 4
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of Saul Bellow's Nobel Lecture by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Bellow, Nobel Lectures, 1978-1981 (bulk), 1953 (memo), 1975 (postcard) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Finanical records, Bellow, Nobel Lectures, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Manuscript, Bellow, Nobel Lectures, December 12, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Manuscript reprint, Bellow, Nobel Lectures, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Manuscript revision, Bellow, Nobel Lectures, May 1, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript with revisions, Bellow, Nobel Lectures, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Sample colophon, title page, paper samples, and complete set of unbound signatures, Bellow, Nobel Lectures, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series IV: Kate Millett, Elegy For Sita, Targ Editions No. 5
  Correspondence, production materials, and press related to the publication of Kate Millett's Elegy For Sita by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Millett, Elegy For Sita, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Financial records, Millett, Elegy For Sita, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Orders, Millett, Elegy For Sita, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Unbound signatures, Millett, Elegy For Sita, November 15, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Printing specs, sample title page, Millett, Elegy For Sita, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Press clippings, Millett, Elegy For Sita, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series V: Richard Brautigan, The Tokyo-Montana Express, Targ Editions No. 6
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of Richard Brautigan's The Tokyo-Montana Express by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Brautigan, The Tokyo-Montana Express, 1979-1981 (bulk), 1994 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Financial records, Brautigan, The Tokyo-Montana Express, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Two proofs, one copy corrected by author, Brautigan, The Tokyo-Montana Express, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Unbound signatures and colophon, Brautigan, The Tokyo-Montana Express, December 21, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Printing samples, Brautigan, The Tokyo-Montana Express, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, Brautigan, The Tokyo-Montana Express, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Series VI: Chester Himes, A Case of Rape, Targ Editions No. 7
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of Chester Himes's A Case of Rape by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Himes, A Case of Rape, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Financial records, Himes, A Case of Rape, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Orders, Himes, A Case of Rape, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Series VII: Laura Riding, Description of Life, Targ Editions No. 8
  Correspondence, production materials, and press related to the publication of Laura Riding's Description of Life by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Riding, Description of Life, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, Riding, Description of Life, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Financial records, Riding, Description of Life, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Orders, Riding, Description of Life, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Complete Manuscript, Riding, Description of Life, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Proof copy with layout notes and revisions, Riding, Description of Life, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Manuscript proof copy, Riding, Description of Life, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Manuscript revision proof copy, Riding, Description of Life, May 21, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Manuscript revision proof copy, Riding, Description of Life, July 9, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Manuscript proof with corrections, Riding, Description of Life, July 25, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Manuscript fragments, Riding, Description of Life, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Final proof with all revisions, Riding, Description of Life, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Uncorrected proof (red), Riding, Description of Life, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Uncorrected proof (off-white), Riding, Description of Life, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Uncorrected proof (black), Riding, Description of Life June, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Uncorrected proof (dark yellow), Riding, Description of Life, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Uncorrected proof (bright yellow), Riding, Description of Life, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Uncorrected proof (beige), Riding, Description of Life, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Uncorrected proof (gray), Riding, Description of Life, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Additional manuscript framents, Riding, Description of Life, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Colophon pages, Riding, Description of Life, June 27, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Press clippings and reviews, Riding, Description of Life, 1973-1980 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Series VIII: Tennessee Williams, Steps Must Be Gentle, Targ Editions No. 9
  Production material related to the publication of Tennessee Williams's Steps Must Be Gentle by Targ Editions.
  - Sample title page, Williams, Steps Must Be Gentle, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Series IX: John Updike, Ego and Art in Walt Whitman, Targ Editions No. 10
  Correspondence, production materials, and press related to the publication of John Updike's Ego and Art in Walt Whitman by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Updike, Ego and Art in Walt Whitman, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Financial records, Updike, Ego and Art in Walt Whitman, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Manuscript, Updike, Ego and Art in Walt Whitman, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Manuscript with author corrections, Updike, Ego and Art in Walt Whitman, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Page proofs on paper sample with layout notes and corrections, Updike, Ego and Art in Walt Whitman, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Paper samples, Updike, Ego and Art in Walt Whitman, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - New York Review of Books reprint, Updike, Ego and Art in Walt Whitman, February 9, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- Series X: Isaac Asimov, Three By Asimov, Targ Editions No. 11
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of Isaac Asimov's Three By Asimov by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Asimov, Three By Asimov, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Financial records, Asimov, Three By Asimov, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Orders, Asimov, Three By Asimov, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Manuscripts: Found!; True Love; The Last Answer; Fair Exchange?, Asimov, Three By Asimov, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Manuscripts: Found!; True Love; The Last Answer; Fair Exchange?, Asimov, Three By Asimov, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Manuscript copy: The Last Answer; True Love; Fair Exchange?, Asimov, Three By Asimov, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Unbound signatures, Asimov, Three By Asimov, undated (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Colophon pages, Asimov, Three By Asimov, April 15, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Paper samples, Asimov, Three By Asimov, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Author photograph, Asimov, Three By Asimov, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 77)
- Series XI: John Updike, Hawthorne's Creed, Targ Editions No. 12
  Correspondence, production materials, and press related to the publication of John Updike's Hawthorne's Creed by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Updike, Hawthorne's Creed, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Financial records, Updike, Hawthorne's Creed, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Manuscript with printer's notes, Updike, Hawthorne's Creed, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Unbound signatures and colophon, Updike, Hawthorne's Creed, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Paper samples, Updike, Hawthorne's Creed, undated (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Hawthorne portrait reproductions, Updike, Hawthorne's Creed, undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Clippings, Updike, Hawthorne's Creed, July 20, 1981; June 20, 1993, 1981, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 84)
- Series XII: Diane Wakoski, Saturn's Rings, Targ Editions No. 14
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of Diane Wakoski's Saturn's Rings by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Wakoski, Saturn's Rings, 1971-1982 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Financial records, Wakoski, Saturn's Rings, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Manuscript and introduction, Wakoski, Saturn's Rings, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Sample tittle page, colophon, and unbound signatures, Wakoski, Saturn's Rings, undated (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Paper samples, Wakoski, Saturn's Rings, undated (Box 4, Folder 89)
- Series XIII: D. R. Bensen, Irene, Good-Night, Embellished by Edward Gorey, Targ Editions No. 15
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of D. R. Bensen's Irene, Good-Night, with frontispiece by Edward Gorey, by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Bensen, Gorey, Irene, Good-Night, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Financial records, Bensen, Gorey, Irene, Good-Night, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Orders, Bensen, Gorey, Irene, Good-Night, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Original manuscript with revisions, Bensen, Gorey, Irene, Good-Night, January 27, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Unbound signatures, Bensen, Gorey, Irene, Good-Night, undated (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Colophon samples, Bensen, Gorey, Irene, Good-Night, undated (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Sample cover material, Bensen, Gorey, Irene, Good-Night, undated (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Gorey woodcut, Bensen, Gorey, Irene, Good-Night, undated (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Sherlock Holmes prints by Sam Green, Bensen, Gorey, Irene, Good-Night, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Ellery Queen magazine, January 1984: first appearance of Irene, Good-Night, Bensen, Gorey, Irene, Good-Night (Box 4, Folder 99)
- Series XIV: Marguerite Yourcenar, The Alms of Alcippe, Targ Editions No. 16
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of Marguerite Yourcenar's The Alms of Alcippe by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Yourcenar, The Alms of Alcippe, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Financial records, Yourcenar, The Alms of Alcippe, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Orders, Yourcenar, The Alms of Alcippe, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Manuscript, Yourcenar, The Alms of Alcippe, undated (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Full set unbound signatures, Yourcenar, The Alms of Alcippe, November 19, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Assorted unbound signatures, signed unbound colophon page, Yourcenar, The Alms of Alcippe, November 12, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Author photograph, Yourcenar, The Alms of Alcippe, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 106)
- Series XV: Theodore Low De Vinne, The First Editor: Aldus Pius Manutius, Woodcuts by Antonio Frasconi, Targ Editions No. 17
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of Frasconi and De Vinne's The First Editor: Aldus Pius Manutius by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Frasconi, De Vinne, The First Editor, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Financial records, Frasconi, De Vinne, The First Editor, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Orders, Frasconi, De Vinne, The First Editor, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Printing samples, paper samples, Frasconi, De Vinne, The First Editor, undated (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Unbound signatures: first proof, Frasconi, De Vinne, The First Editor, undated (Box 5, Folder 111)
- Series XVI: Jorge Amado, The Miracle of the Birds, Targ Editions No. 18
  Correspondence, production materials, and press related to the publication of Jorge Amado's The Miracle of the Birds by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Amado, The Miracle of the Birds, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Financial records, Amado, The Miracle of the Birds, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Orders, Amado, The Miracle of the Birds, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Unbound signatures, Amado, The Miracle of the Birds, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Sample cover material, Amado, The Miracle of the Birds, undated (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Press clippings, Amado, The Miracle of the Birds, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 117)
- Series XVII: James A. Michener, Collectors, Forgers--And A Writer: A Memoir, Forward by John F. Fleming, Targ Editions No. 19
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of James A. Michener's Collectors, Forgers--And A Writer: A Memoir by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Michener, Collectors, Forgers..., 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Financial records, Michener, Collectors, Forgers..., 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Orders, Michener, Collectors, Forgers..., 1983-1993 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Title page and foreword, Michener, Collectors, Forgers..., 1983 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Title page and colophon sample, Michener, Collectors, Forgers..., 1983 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Type samples, Michener, Collectors, Forgers..., undated (Box 5, Folder 123)
- Series XVIII: W. D. Snodgrass, Vivaldi's Four Seasons, Targ Editions No. 20
  Correspondence and production materials related to the publication of W. D. Snodgrass's translation of Antonio Vivaldi's The Four Seasons by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Snodgrass, The Four Seasons, 1981-1985 (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Financial correspondence, Snodgrass, The Four Seasons, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - Orders, Snodgrass, The Four Seasons, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Manuscript (camera ready), Snodgrass, The Four Seasons, undated (Box 6, Folder 167)
  - Manuscript fragments, Snodgrass, The Four Seasons, undated (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - Unbound signatures, Snodgrass, The Four Seasons, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Colophon versions, Snodgrass, The Four Seasons, undated (Box 6, Folder 130)
- Series XIX: Wallace Shawn, Our Late Night, Targ Editions No. 21
  Correspondence, production materials, and press related to the publication of Wallace Shawn's play Our Late Night by Targ Editions.
  - Correspondence, Shawn, Our Late Night, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Financial records, Shawn, Our Late Night, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Orders, Shawn, Our Late Night, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Bound manuscript: The Old Man, Shawn, Our Late Night, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 134)